Guide to the World Council of Churches Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Program Divisions, Commissions, Departments, Series IV
  - Department of Information
    - F-Series, 1955-1963 (Box 24, Folder 168-169)
    - Releases, 1955-1961 (Box 24, Folder 170-175)
    - U.S. Press Releases, 1951-1961 (Box 25, Folder 176-180)
    - World Council Courier / Ecumenical Courier, 1943-1968 (Box 25, Folder 181)
  - Department of Reconstruction and Interchurch Aid
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1942-1949 (Box 26, Folder 182)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1951-1954 (Box 26, Folder 183)
  - Department on Church and Society (Division of Studies)
    - Material related to "The Common Christian Responsibility Towards Areas of Rapid Social Change", 1955-1959 (Box 28, Folder 194-196)
    - Project papers on "The Common Christian Responsibility Towards Areas of Rapid Social Change", 1956-1958 (Box 28, Folder 197-199)
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1955-1959 (Box 28, Folder 200)
    - Issues of Anticipation: Christian Social Thought in Future Perspective, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 496)
    - "Christians and Social Change in Latin America" - Huampani, Peru, 1961 (Box 71, Folder 496)
  - Department of Cooperation of Men and Women in Church and Society (Under Division of Ecumenical Action)
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1954-1961 (Box 27, Folder 189)
  - Department of Cooperation of Men and Women in Church, Family and Society
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1962-1968 (Box 27, Folder 189A)
  - Department on Evangelism
    - General, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 201)
  - Department on Missionary Studies
    - General, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 201A)
  - Department on Studies in Mission and Evangelism
    - General, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 398)
  - Department on Laity
    - General, 1951-1959 (Box 27, Folder 190)
  - Department on Women in Church and Society
    - General, 1958-1976 (Box 27, Folder 191)
  - Desk for Documentation Concerning East-European Churches
    - General, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 192)
  - Dialogue with People of Living Faiths and Ideologies
    - (see: Sub-unit on Dialogue with People of Living Faiths and Ideologies)
  - Division of Ecumenical Action
    - Miscellaneous: includes materials from and concerning the review Istina and Roman Catholic views on the ecumenical movement, 1954-1968 (Box 27, Folder 193)
  - Division of Inter-Church Aid and Service to Refugees
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1955-1961 (Box 26, Folder 183A-185)
    - Serials, 1958-1960 (Box 26, Folder 186)
    - Ecumenical Church Loan Fund (ECLOF), 1957-1960 (Box 26, Folder 187)
  - Division of Studies
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1957 (Box 28, Folder 193A)
    - Bulletin, 1962, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 193B)
    - Program Budget, n.d. (1957?) (Box 28, Folder 203)
    - Background Information for Church and Society, 1954-1961 (Box 29, Folder 204-206)
    - Study document, 1956, 1959 (Box 68, Folder 472)
    - Occasional papers, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 473)
    - Joint Consultation on Biblical Hermeneutics (with Commission on Faith and Order), 1967 (Box 67, Folder 469)
  - Ecumenical Institute
    - Program information, 1948-1961 (Box 30, Folder 207-213)
    - Correspondence, publications, 1947-1957 (Box 30, Folder 214)
    - Reports, 1972, 1973 (Box 68, Folder 474)
  - Finance Committeee
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1961 (Box 31, Folder 215-216)
  - Friends of the World Council of Churches
    - (see: Series VI)
  - General Secretariat
    - General, 1949 (Box 56, Folder 371A)
  - Joint Committee of the International Missionary Council and World Council of Churches
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-1957 (Box 57, Folder 377-379)
  - Office of Family Ministries
    - General, 1974-1977 (Box 63, Folder 416-418)
  - Orthodox Task Force
    - Material transferred to cataloged collection.
  - Programme of Justice, Peace and the Integrity of Creation
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1987 (Box 60, Folder 400)
    - Resource materials, 1988 (Box 70, Folder 486-488)
    - Resource materials, 1988 (Box 71, Folder 489)
  - Programme on Theological Education
    - General, 1983-1988 (Box 61, Folder 405, 405A)
  - Programme to Combat Racism
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1970-1980, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 220-221)
    - Special Fund: Grants approved by the Executive Committee of the W.C.C., 1976 (Box 68, Folder 476)
  - Programme Unit on Education and Renewal
    - Education newsletter, 1982-1986 (Box 61, Folder 407)
    - General, 1983-1988 (Box 63, Folder 414, 415)
    - Communication (Nos. 19-40), 1978-1979 (Box 68, Folder 476)
  - Programme Unit on Faith and Witness/Dialogue with People of Living Faiths and Ideologies
    - "Biblical Interpretation and Its Bearing on Christian Attitudes Regarding the Situation in the Middle East", 1974 Jan 21-26 (Box 68, Folder 477)
    - Materials related to Jewish-Christian relations, 1975, 1978 (Box 71, Folder 490)
  - Programme Unit on Justice and Service
    - Newsletters, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 370)
  - Refugee Division
    - General (see also: Department of Inter-church Aid and Service to Refugees), 1949 (Box 26, Folder 182B)
  - Secretariat on Evangelism
    - General, 1949-1950 (Box 56, Folder 371)
  - Secretariat on Racial and Ethnic Relations
    - General (see also: Programme to Combat Racism), 1964-1965 (Box 32, Folder 222-223)
  - Secretariat on Religious Liberty
    - General (see also: Commission on Religious Liberty), 1962-1964 (Box 28, Folder 202)
  - Study Department
    - Organization and planning (see also: Division of Studies; See Series I for material prior to 1949), 1949-1953 (Box 35, Folder 238-240)
    - "The Bible and the Church's Message to the World", 1949-1953 (Box 35, Folder 241-243)
    - "Christian Action in Society", 1949-1953 (Box 35, Folder 244-247)
    - "Evangelism", 1947-1951 (Box 36, Folder 248)
    - "Theological Trends from 1900-1950", 1951-1952 (Box 36, Folder 249)
    - "Christian Faith and Psychotherapy" (Box 36, Folder 250)
    - Information Bulletin, 1950 (Box 36, Folder 251)
    - Ecumenical Studies, 1951-1954 (Box 36, Folder 252)
    - Background Information, 1951-1954 (Box 36, Folder 253)
    - Bulletin, 1955-1959 (Box 36, Folder 254)
  - Sub-Unit on Church and Society
    - Church and Society, 1984-1987 (Box 32, Folder 223A)
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1986 (Box 58, Folder 395)
  - Sub-Unit on Dialogue with People of Living Faiths and Ideologies
    - Study Encounter, 1973, 1975 (Box 59, Folder 397)
    - "Biblical Interpretation and Its Bearing on Christian Attitudes Regarding the Situation in the Middle East", 1974 Jan 21-26 (Box 68, Folder 477)
  - Sub-Unit on Education
    - Scholarship Newsletter, 1981-1982 (Box 44, Folder 301)
  - Sub-Unit on Women in Church and Society
    - Miscellaneous publications (see also: Department on Women in Church and Society), 1976-1985 (Box 46, Folder 313)
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1986-1987 (Box 58, Folder 393)
  - Sub-Unit on Renewal and Congregational Life
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1986-1987 (Box 58, Folder 394)
  - Theological Education Fund
    - General, 1954-1977 (Box 33, Folder 224)
    - Minutes, documents, 1967-1977 (Box 63, Folder 419)
    - Reports, 1963-1977 (Box 71, Folder 491)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, 1960s-1970s (Box 71, Folder 492)
  - Youth Department
    - General, 1948-1960 (Box 34, Folder 236-237)
- Miscellaneous Publications, n.d.; Series V
  - Constitution, public relations materials, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 255)
  - Public relations material, miscellany, 1938-1960 (Box 37, Folder 256-257)
  - Worship Service, program material, 1955-1958, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 258)
  - Program material (Box 58, Folder 390-391)
  - Resource Sharing Book, 1985-1988 (Box 62, Folder 413)
  - Resource Sharing Book, 1983, 1989, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 420)
  - Ecumenical Biography (Box 68, Folder 478)
  - Historical calendar, 1948-1988 (Box 68, Folder 479)
  - WCC Publications, 1992 Sep-1993 Mar (Box 68, Folder 480)
  - Manual to facilitate bibliographical research through the direct enquire system of the library of the W.C.C. (WCC Library Series, 1), 1989 (Box 68, Folder 481)
  - Directory 2005 (Box 71, Folder 493)
  - Two issues of "Women in a Changing World", 1989 (Box 71, Folder 494)
  - "The Church and Beyond the Church: A Study of the World Council of Churches" by Harold F. Hufendick (Box 71, Folder 495)
  - "Composite Statement of Needs", 1978 (Box 71, Folder 497)
  - "Healing as Empowerment" Discovering Grace in Community" by Usha Jesudasan and Gert Ruppell, ca. 2005 (Box 71, Folder 498)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets and articles, 1970-2005 (Box 71, Folder 499)
- Related Organizations, Series VI
  - American Committee for the World Council of Churches
    - Correspondence, minutes reports, periodicals (see also: United States Conference of the WCC), 1939-1949 (Box 19, Folder 136-138)
  - Commission for World Council Service
    - General, 1945, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 372)
  - Commission on Christian Unity
    - General, 1940 (Box 57, Folder 373)
  - Conseil Suisse des Missions Evangeliques, 1955
    - General, 1955 (Box 57, Folder 373A)
  - Ecumenical Advocacy Alliance
    - Action Guide, 2005 (Box 71, Folder 500)
  - Ecumenical Press Service
    - General, 1948-1950 (Box 57, Folder 374)
    - General, 1987-1988 (Box 61, Folder 409, 410)
  - Friends of the World Council of Churches
    - General, 1943-1953 (Box 57, Folder 375)
  - International Council of Religious Education: Joint Committee on Ecumenical Education of the International Council of Religious Education and the Midwest Committee of WCC
    - General, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 376)
  - International Missionary Council
    - Joint Committee of the IMC and WCC - Agendae and Reports, 1946 (Box 57, Folder 377)
    - Joint Committee of the IMC and WCC - Miscellaneous minutes, memos, and reports, 1947-1956 (Box 57, Folder 378)
    - Joint Committee of the IMC and WCC - Minutes and reports, 1957 (Box 57, Folder 379)
    - Program Structure and Staffing - Preliminary papers re. Relations between IMC and WCC, 1947-1949 (Box 57, Folder 380)
    - Miscellaneous Papers re. Integration of IMC and WCC, 1951-1960 (Box 57, Folder 381)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, Articles, and Reports on Relations of Younger Churches to IMC and WCC, 1943-1948, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 382)
    - Joint Commission on East India - Minutes, 1948 (Box 57, Folder 383)
    - East Asian Christian Conference/Bangkok - Miscellaneous Papers, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 384)
    - The East Asia Christian Literature Conference - Minutes, 1951 (Box 57, Folder 385)
    - East Asia Secretariat - Minutes of Consultation held in Wattana Wittaya Academy, Bangkok, 1956 (Box 57, Folder 386)
    - Minutes of the Enlarged Meeting and the Committee of the International Missionary Council, 1952 (Box 68, Folder 482)
  - Jewish-Christian Consultation
    - General, 1972 (Box 68, Folder 483)
  - United States Conference of the World Council of Churches
    - Correspondence, minutes, reports (see also: American Committee for the World Council of Churches, 1949-1961, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 225-235)
    - Work Group on Education for Ecumenism, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 235A)
    - U.S. Press Releases, 1951-1961 (Box 25, Folder 176-180)
    - World Council Courier / Ecumenical Courier, 1943-1968, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 181)
  - World Christian Youth Commission: Consultation on Evangelical and Ecumenical Responsibilities
    - General, 1957 (Box 57, Folder 387)